George Marriott

Contact information:

Email: marriottg94@hotmail.co.uk

Phone: 07572886233

Github: https://gmarriott.github.io/portfolio **Address:** Stockport, Greater Manchester

I am an experienced software developer with a keen interest in learning new technologies and staying up to date with the latest development concepts. Since leaving university I have made it a key interest of mine to stay relevant in an always updating technology sector. This has led me to develop professional applications for companies in a variety of different sectors. I jump at opportunities to improve my character and very much enjoy learning by tackling tasks head on.

Experience:

BrightHR - February 2024 to Present - Senior Frontend Engineer

I am currently involved in the DotCom team, helping to optimise the user experience on our site through SEO improvements and by creating an efficient and satisfying user experience.

Skills: React.js | Redux | Typescript | NextJS | DatoCMS | Storybook | Tailwind | SEO Optimisation | Git | Management Skills

Career Break - September 2023 to February 2024

At the start of September I took time out of work to travel. I visited Australia, New Zealand, Indonesia and Thailand. I experienced all new cultures and became more confident in myself, meeting lots of new friends along my journey. I conquered a fear of extreme heights by skydiving and took some time to achieve my PADI open water diving qualification.

Skills Gained: Appreciation of other cultures and ways of living | Personal connections | PADI Open Water Qualification

XDesign - October 2022 to September 2023 - Software Engineer

While at XDesign I was involved in building features and updating existing code for our external client Fanduel. I worked closely on the internal promotion creation system to deliver the best possible experience for the users. This included a variety of tasks one of which was streamlining existing features so the user flow would be improved.

Skills: React.js | Redux | Typescript | Bootstrap | Webpack | Node.js | Storybook | Jest | Performance Testing | Git | Java | AWS

Tutorful - September 2019 to September 2022 - Software Engineer

During my time at Tutorful I was part of a development team tasked with creating and forwarding features available on the Tutorful platform. I created many features during my time with the company, one of my major contributions was that I was involved in expanding the platform to distribute in Ireland. This involved creating bespoke landing pages and expanding our backend infrastructure to handle the new currency. I also contributed to saving development time by creating reusable atomic components to be used on the project.

Skills: Vue.js | Vuex | Typescript | Atomic Design | SQL | Laravel | Google Optimise | Amplitude | Troubleshooting | AWS

Twinkl Educational Publishing - May 2017 to September 2019 - Web Developer

I was part of the development team that was dedicated to optimising the user experience and efficiency of online applications used by the company. Within this role, the team I was part of was tasked with creating a resource curation system, which allowed our colleagues to create the resources that drive the main Twinkl web pages. I was able to improve the feature set on offer within the system as well as improve the performance and efficiency of pre-existing components.

Skills: React.js | Redux | Node.js | PHP | SQL | MongoDB | CSS | SASS | Git | Workflows | HTML | Agile | Scrum | CI

Kitlocker.com - May 2015 to August 2016 - Junior Web Developer

As part of my university placement at Kitlocker I was able to develop my programming knowledge as well as improve upon my teamwork and communication skills. One project I undertook was building and testing a frontend system which utilised the Nike EDI ordering platform to place product orders to Nike dynamically and in bulk, upon completing this task we found it saved time when the product came to being shipped. I felt comfortable working in a small team and was able to adapt quickly to overcome obstacles and deliver projects to the best of my ability.

Skills: Javascript | HTML | CSS | APIs | PHP | SQL | Time management | Teamwork | Continuous Integration | Debugging

Projects:

Building my portfolio.

At the beginning of my second year at university we were introduced to the 'Web Application Module'. After being taught the basics of HTML 5 and PHP we were assigned to build an events website. Being interested in starting my own portfolio I took the assignment as being a crucial starting point to learning the essentials of web development as well as how to debug. From this I expanded on my existing knowledge of web frameworks to use React.js to create a portfolio site for myself. I found this as a useful experience for learning different web development frameworks. My portfolio can be viewed by using the following link: https://gmarriott.github.io/portfolio/

Leading development on a mobile application.

For one of my university modules we had the opportunity to develop a system for a real client and try to capture their requirements. Our client was one of the organisers for the Sheffield Hallam Art Show. She wanted a mobile app to improve the publicity of the show and to have navigation functionality to guide users to the different show locations. I led the team and assigned tasks based on who was best equipped to complete them. I had to keep in contact with the client and make sure her requirements were being fulfilled. After the development process was over my group achieved positive feedback from both the client and our assessors.

Education:

Sheffield Hallam University - 2013 to 2017 - Software Engineering - First Class Honours

Studying Software Engineering at Sheffield Hallam University, left me with invaluable knowledge, and the ability to learn and adapt quickly to pick up new programming languages. During my course I was able to experiment with various technologies which, in turn, allowed me to actively engage with the subject. Upon completion of the course I felt comfortable with the software development process, which helped me to achieve a First Class Honours.

Boston Grammar Sixth Form - 2011 to 2013: A levels - Media (B), ICT (C), Religious Studies (C) and General Studies (D).

Notable Achievements: "Lessons from Auschwitz" Ambassador.

Giles Academy - 2007 to 2011: 8 GCSE's A-C including Science (B), Maths (C) and English (A).

Skills:

Programming:

During my studies I have engaged fully with various languages including PHP, C# and JavaScript. For my final year project I built a dynamic tracker application using the MEAN stack technologies, this gave me some exposure to different JavaScript frameworks such as Node.js and Express.js. I learned valuable concepts when it came to development, including object oriented programing and user interface design. I incorporated a NoSQL database with MongoDB and served it to the client using Angular. I find with every language comes new and exciting challenges and am eager to expand my knowledge and master other languages like Python and Ruby. With this experience I was able to transfer this knowledge into the workplace and gain professional experience as a developer.

Teamwork and Agile working:

Throughout my time in the workplace I have adhered to an agile way of working. Using this methodology and incorporating both daily stand-ups and sprints I have been able to effectively manage my time and collaborate within teams to produce high quality work.

Interests and Hobbies:

I have always been a very active individual, I enjoy jogging, hiking, cycling and maintaining my overall fitness. I have recently taken up paddleboarding and have taken my own board out to various places in the countryside. I am also an avid traveler and love sharing stories of my different experiences traveling around the world.

References: If a reference is required please get in touch, I will be able to provide these upon request.